<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learn on Often Bearing Metaphoric Tense</title>
    <link>http://theanalyst.github.io/tags/learn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learn on Often Bearing Metaphoric Tense</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved 2012-15</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://theanalyst.github.io/tags/learn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Silent Observer&#39;s Metamorphosis</title>
      <link>http://theanalyst.github.io/Tech/learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theanalyst.github.io/Tech/learn/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;My friend, Jinto, wrote a blog-post titled
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://untold-opinion.blogspot.in/2012/12/transitioning-from-learners-to-observers.html&#34;&gt;Transitioning from learners to observers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, which talks about the
increasing transition from a learner to being a casual observer of
things in this digital era. The availability of a wide range of tools
these days to do &lt;em&gt;almost anything&lt;/em&gt;, has slowly reduced the need to
learn, a very valid observation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the usefulness of tools is great, it might fail miserably when
you want things certain way, and the tool may not be designed for
that. A real life example would be this: in college, ever since the
second year, I was using a software called, LyX for creating
reports. LyX allows you to create LaTeX documents without the need to
actually know TeX, so I never felt the necessity to learn LaTeX, for
real. While LyX is a great tool for creating documents, if an error
crept in documents somehow, or if you want to create a report with a
custom template, then it fails miserably. (Also at the time I was in
college, LyX had no support for extended unicode, using XeTeX and the
like etc.) So towards the end I had to learn TeX the hard way, when I
was pressed for time. A recent conversation took place on #emacs in
irc&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f6ecf5148c4e37e58f4f14fcdc127e45:irc&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f6ecf5148c4e37e58f4f14fcdc127e45:irc&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, where someone asked about the right tools for LaTeX, and
possibilities of LyX etc., for which a reply came as while there are a
number of tools which may generate LaTeX files for you without having
to learn it, errors it generate might set your hair on fire (and this
mostly by experience, takes place on the previous night of the
deadline, when you see cryptic latex errors that have no end)&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:f6ecf5148c4e37e58f4f14fcdc127e45:emacs&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:f6ecf5148c4e37e58f4f14fcdc127e45:emacs&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that is in tandem with the declining reading habit in
this era is the works of literature being converted to movies. While
movies of literary works may certainly be the easy way out, it may not
always do justice to the author’s creative genius in every case. (Of
the top 20 IMDB movies, 11 are based on literary works) Reading the 7
Harry Potter books will help in realising why a muggle like
J.K.Rowling is a billionaire. While movies tell a great story, the
reading experience is unparalleled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on, one of the reasons for the metamorphosis of a learner to
being a silent observer, is the fact that, you&amp;rsquo;re in a comfort zone
when there is a lazy tool to do things for you, and hence there is no
real need to try to do things differently. And mostly the learning
process gets initiated only when you &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; things to work in a
certain way. For me, this blog was an experiment to learn a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt;
webdesign, while I was comfortable with blogger all along, the fact
is, you can blog a lifetime in blogger and still need not know what
HTML or css looks like. My requirement was to make a decent site that
looks ok in mobile as well (a responsive web design experiment, as
some would call it), while the output may not be what you can compare
with a web developer&amp;rsquo;s design, at least I learnt the process of
writing a half decent responsive media queries in css. There may be
many talented people who can generate a better looking website in less
than a tenth of the time I used to create mine, but that certainly
doesn&amp;rsquo;t take away the knowledge aquired in trying to do it, and I
believe that is important.  As said in article at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://simpleprogrammer.com/2012/09/23/learning-to-learn/&#34;&gt;Simple Programmer&lt;/a&gt;, the true goal of &lt;em&gt;learning&lt;/em&gt;, which is the
ability to put knowledge into action. An english philospher’s famous
words were this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The great aim of education is not knowledge but action”
&lt;small&gt;Herbert Spencer&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately it is picking up something you end up loving and learning
about it. Trying to do things in a different way can definitely open
new channels.  To conclude, I will quote something from
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tom_Peters&#34;&gt;Tom Peters&lt;/a&gt;, a quote often misattributed to Leanardo Da Vinci, on innovation and success:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Life is pretty simple: You do some stuff. Most fails. Some works. You
do more of what works. If it works big, others quickly copy it. Then
you do something else. The trick is the doing something else.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S if you haven’t clicked the link to the article
&lt;a href=&#34;http://simpleprogrammer.com/2012/09/23/learning-to-learn/&#34;&gt;Learning to learn&lt;/a&gt; at Simple Programmer, do it now, certainly
worth a read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;foot-notes:f6ecf5148c4e37e58f4f14fcdc127e45&#34;&gt;Foot Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;was taking place in #emacs, well, it all started with TeXmacs
+ emacs, though ultimately I guess the guy settled with TeXmaker. The
former has a (dis)advantage of a steeper learning curve (and might be
an overkill if your only aim is to generate tex files, though proviedes an unobtrusive learning environment nonetheless)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f6ecf5148c4e37e58f4f14fcdc127e45:irc&#34;&gt;If you, like me, were wondering about how a TeX conversation
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f6ecf5148c4e37e58f4f14fcdc127e45:irc&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:f6ecf5148c4e37e58f4f14fcdc127e45:emacs&#34;&gt;Also, the channel being emacs, the advice was to use AucTeX
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:f6ecf5148c4e37e58f4f14fcdc127e45:emacs&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>