<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Btrfs on Often Bearing Metaphoric Tense</title>
    <link>http://abhishekl.in/tags/btrfs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Btrfs on Often Bearing Metaphoric Tense</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved 2012-15</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://abhishekl.in/tags/btrfs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing my Root partition full on btrfs</title>
      <link>http://abhishekl.in/post/Tech/btrfs-snapper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhishekl.in/post/Tech/btrfs-snapper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past 2 days my Laptop running openSUSE tumbleweed was complaining of
root system full, I was on a spree deleting packages which tend to be on the
heavier side, generally clearing TeX alone would suffice, however this time the
root partition of around 28 G was showing 99% utilization&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After clearing up many development headers, killing of java etc. I managed to
free a good 2G of space, however within a few minutes, &lt;code&gt;df&lt;/code&gt; again revealed the
root partition was full, also cleared out the obvious logs in &lt;code&gt;/var/log&lt;/code&gt; and a
coredump that was in the 100 MB ranges. Funnily enough after removal of a few
packages the root partition seemed to be growing in usage rather than shrinking.
The systemd journal was around 800 MB in size, since I assumed this was growing
as a result of many packages getting killed etc, I found out that the journal
was around 800 MB in size, not much, but still enough to get a breathing space.
Trimmed old logs using the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# journalctl --vacuum-size=200M 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However even this was shortlived (running a du on the &lt;code&gt;/var/log&lt;/code&gt; folder revealed that there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any space occupied by logs at all). Finally assumed it because of the root filesystem btrfs doing something funny. Initially assumed it was some metadata mismanagement, (as the installed applications were around 8-10G, in a 28 G partition), tried various options according to &lt;a href=&#34;http://marc.merlins.org/perso/btrfs/post_2014-05-04_Fixing-Btrfs-Filesystem-Full-Problems.html&#34;&gt;this blog&lt;/a&gt;, but in my case data was itself shown as using around 27G. Finally remembered the snapshotting feature of btrfs. So found out that the OS takes a snapshot before and after any system update activity, which is of course convenient if an update ends up screwing the system as you can always boot from a different snapshot. However in my case, I&amp;rsquo;m really not very keen on keeping a lot of snapshots, as most of the development I do has moved to some sort of virtualenv wherever possible, and also since all my data lives in a different home and data partition, I&amp;rsquo;m kind of okay to reinstall the OS, in case an upgrade does end up bringing the system to an unusable state. So in order to clean up the snapshot &lt;code&gt;snapper&lt;/code&gt;  is the tool that helps manage snapshots (has a GUI too I think). Doing a &lt;code&gt;snapper ls&lt;/code&gt; revealed that I had around close to 30 snapshots, which explained why the root partition got full. The command to delete the snapshot is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# snapper rm &amp;lt;snapid&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deleting all the snapshots except for the current and the first snapshot, I finally ended up getting 16 Gigs of free space. Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll not run out of root space for sometime :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>