<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gtd on Often Bearing Metaphoric Tense</title>
    <link>http://abhishekl.in/tags/gtd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gtd on Often Bearing Metaphoric Tense</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved 2012-15</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://abhishekl.in/tags/gtd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The 30 Day Rule</title>
      <link>http://abhishekl.in/post/Rants/30-day-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhishekl.in/post/Rants/30-day-rule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, I always take up a resolution to write more. But every time I begin
to write, I end up procrastinating over hitting publish button, often thinking
it is not world ready yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw this TED video, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/matt_cutts_try_something_new_for_30_days&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Try something new for 30 days&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. In this short and
lucid talk, Matt Curtis, a Google engineer, explains the 30 day rule, where
if there is something that you&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to do, but keep pushing it off,
try it for 30 days. 30 days is a good amount of time to almost make it a
practice, and you would never believe how different things turn out because of
trying something for 30 days. So this is my start to try writing &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;
(hopefully in this blog) for 30 days. I hope not to spend more than 30 minutes
per post, so it would be a rather unorganized blog, but at least I hope to show
up and write rather than it being a thought in an obscure corner of my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I can end up publishing lot of posts that were in draft mode for a lot
of time now. Often the content will not as polished as the others I&amp;rsquo;ve published
(but when is the last time I edited something I&amp;rsquo;ve already published) and trying
to make it a habit to writing more. Let us see where this ends up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>