<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hyperbolic Monologues</title><link>http://theanalyst.github.com</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://theanalyst.github.com/feeds/rants.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hello World</title><link>http://theanalyst.github.com/hello-world.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you're reading this, it means that I have successfully started
blogging again (&lt;em&gt;yay!&lt;/em&gt;). As the more perceptive of you might have
realized, this blog isn't hosted at &lt;em&gt;blogger&lt;/em&gt; anymore well this new
avatar is powered by &lt;a href="pelican.notmyidea.org"&gt;pelican&lt;/a&gt;, an awesome
static blogging engine written in python and served by github pages,
(of course the second part should be intuitionally obvious, given the
url atm). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the sabbatical from &lt;em&gt;blogosphere&lt;/em&gt; has been long, it was more
because of lack of anything to post rather than too busy to post
anything, and now I'm back from a questionably long self-imposed
exile. And life has been relatively smooth in the interlude,(though my
last post was from college, which I dearly miss now) and I'm a
graduand now with a job going along just fine and learning new things
in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I'm still in the process of importing previous posts and
comments from blogger (read I am yet to decide whether the pain is
worth it or not), you should have fun reading the blog with its
current content which should be narcissistic links to me-pages. You
should be seeing proper posts being pushed into this url soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have read upto this point, I would urge you to take the leap of
faith, and follow my alter-egos in the parallel universes of
&lt;em&gt;twitterati&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;blogosphere&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">The Analyst</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://theanalyst.github.com/hello-world.html</guid><category>Rants</category></item></channel></rss>