<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Often Bearing Metaphoric Tense</title><link href="theanalyst.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="theanalyst.github.io/feeds/rants.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>theanalyst.github.io/</id><updated>2013-04-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>I'm Back (the hyperbole version)</title><link href="theanalyst.github.io/im-back-the-hyperbole-version.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Abhishek L</name></author><id>tag:,2013-04-01:theanalyst.github.io/im-back-the-hyperbole-version.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the quintessential “I'm back” post in blogosphere, which is
often marked by a blogger coming up with &lt;em&gt;imaginative&lt;/em&gt; reasons
to explain a questionable absence from the virtual world. 
Tempting explanations for, not writing for so long, include 
work pressure, often marked by people blaming work for
(not) following their interests, a generic term, which, writers &amp;amp; artists
lovingly call the writer’s block, to describe their shortage of
creativity. Of course, if you know me, you know the actual reason is
just a cover up for not mentioning my often recurring theme of
procrastination. This time though twitcrastination&lt;sup id="fnref:twit"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:twit" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is to blame
for most of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of late, I have found a new obsession for (micro) blogging in form of
twitter, a service, which apparently,&lt;s&gt; lets you post links to
instagram dinner pics&lt;/s&gt;, helps people to connect to people and
organisations they care about. However, what happens in reality is
explained in part by the graph below.(A certain Gauss must be
twisting &amp;amp; turning in his grave here, for the blatant abuse of normal
distributions that is about to follow &lt;sup id="fnref:xkcd"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:xkcd" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="xkcd_productivity" src="images/productivity.png" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing the world's desire to shorten its verbosity, and the disturbing
increase in TL;DR statuses, I am thinking of killling my blog to 
embrace the merry little challenges of microblogging. 
Why should anything stand the test of time and be etched in stone?
Its 2013, ephemeral (like twitter statuses) is the way to go for your thoughts and actions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:twit"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Procrastination enabled by use of twitter, a term which the 
twitterati obsessively uses to explain their apparent lack of productivity&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:twit" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:xkcd"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XKCD plots,  the cornerstone of any descriptive
stats, XKCDify any matplotlib graph; details &lt;a href="http://jakevdp.github.com/blog/2012/10/07/xkcd-style-plots-in-matplotlib"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and source &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/theanalyst/5284221"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:xkcd" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:blog"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;line stolen from the title of a friend’s awesome &lt;a href="http://istheurlavailable.wordpress.com"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:blog" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 3 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="Rants"></category><category term="Writing"></category><category term="Twitter"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello World</title><link href="theanalyst.github.io/hello-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-08T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Abhishek L</name></author><id>tag:,2012-06-08:theanalyst.github.io/hello-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you're reading this, it means that I have successfully started
blogging again. As the more perceptive of you might have
realized, this blog isn't hosted at &lt;em&gt;blogger&lt;/em&gt; anymore well this new
avatar is powered by &lt;a href="pelican.notmyidea.org"&gt;pelican&lt;/a&gt;, an awesome
static blogging engine written in python and served by github pages,
(of course the second part should be intuitionally obvious, given the
url atm). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the sabbatical from &lt;em&gt;blogosphere&lt;/em&gt; has been long, it was more
because of lack of anything to post rather than too busy to post
anything, and now I'm back from a questionably long self-imposed
exile. And life has been relatively smooth in the interlude,(though my
last post was from college, which I dearly miss now) and I'm a
graduand now with a job going along just fine and learning new things
in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I'm still in the process of importing previous posts and
comments from blogger (read I am yet to decide whether the pain is
worth it or not), you should have fun reading the blog with its
current content which should be narcissistic links to me-pages. You
should be seeing proper posts being pushed into this url soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have read upto this point, I would urge you to take the leap of
faith, and follow my alter-egos in the parallel universes of
&lt;em&gt;twitterati&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;blogosphere&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Rants"></category></entry></feed>